This week in generative AI, we have
several apps that can do Photoshop level
edits just by speaking to them and some
interesting standardization coming in
when it comes to how you provide agents
with context. That and a few more
stories in a lightweight edition of AI
news you can use. The show that looks at
all the releases in generative AI from
the last week and highlights the ones
that you can use or that matter.
Starting off the story that everybody
has been talking about over the past few
days. Nano Banana, that's the name of
this tool that has been going around on
LM Arena. And if you're not familiar,
this is a platform that ranks various
models on their capabilities. In this
case, Nano Banana is a image editing AI
model. So you give it an image and words
and it edits them. You might have
experienced this concept in Chat GPT.
When you upload a picture and ask for
some edits, it can do that too. But as
you might know in chat GPT with the
image generation tool, if you try to
edit, it will change everything about
the picture, including the look of the
person that you're trying to edit,
making it not even an option for most
use cases. Nano Banana is different, but
it's not like a fully public available
thing. People are rumoring that Google
is testing this tool against other
models on LM Arena. And right now, the
only way to really try to yourself is to
have a little patience and to cycle
through various tools while comparing
two of them in their interface. And then
eventually, you're going to find one
with the name Nana Banana. We did this
for you and tested the image editing
capabilities with a prompt that you can
now see compared to some of the
competition. Now, here's the thing about
the model. It's very good at editing
stuff locally and adhering to your
prompt. Meaning, if you tell it you only
want to edit the jacket and you want to
make it a certain material, it will
actually do it. Whereas most other
models are kind of hit and miss, as you
can see in these examples, it has its
weaknesses with the text, but I was
actually kind of impressed by how good
it is at, for example, replacing a piece
of clothing like we did in this demo
here. And this is giving Photoshop a
real run for its money because this
classic tool to alter images has a
learning curve. Not everybody can just
use that intuitively, whereas everybody
can type what they need into a little
text box and get results. And changing
jackets is just one use case if you
really have the power to accurately edit
images with just words. So you could do
image restoration like turning these
historical photos into something
current. And look at the accuracy
between those two. You can change the
lighting in the scene or take one base
image and recreate that in many other
copies. I mean, look at the character
reference here between the various
shots. And over here they look
surprisingly similar. Whereas with all
other models, usually they just look
like a different person. Chachi being
actually one of the worst ones when it
comes to image reference. So this is
really pushing what's possible with
these image models. And we had even a
second model that I kind of want to
follow the story up with released out of
Quen this week. Quen image edit. And
they lead with this example of one
character into all of these variations.
And again, the character reference on
this is becoming so strong. We've never
really seen it before at this level.
Look, this is the input image and then
you can create all of these variations.
They have a lot more examples on their
blog post. And if you actually want to
try one of these tools, this is the one
that's easy to access. If you go to
chats.quen.ai, you can go in here and
use the image editing tool right in
here. And me and a team have actually
been playing with these tools.
Particularly, this Quinn model is
actually really good at text. And you
can do things like giving it a thumbnail
like this one of me riding a camel
looking for the best AI search engine.
And then if I tell it to change the text
to best burrito in town, just don't
forget to enable image edit right there.
Let's have a look. And that is not
perfect. Let's give it one more try.
Meanwhile, I'll show you an example that
came up during our testing here. It just
nailed it right. The gradient stayed the
same. It got the font exactly right.
Let's see if we can replicate that here
in our live testing. No, it's really
having troubles with the word burrito.
One final try maybe. No, actually did
not work flawlessly. So, it looks like
it might work for a word or two, but
four is too much. And Nano Banana isn't
even good at text. It's just good at
everything else. So, let's try one more.
Replace the map with a smartphone. Okay,
hands are kind of good, but not great
either. So, yeah, clearly some of these
Nano Banana examples are the most
impressive thing we've seen out there,
but it's kind of hard to access for now.
But interesting as an example of how
quick even these image models are
progressing these days. One thing that
all top AI models like GP5, Gemini 2.5
Pro, and Opus 4.1 have in common is that
they're incredible at writing code. But
just producing good code isn't what
truly makes a developer or a dev team
great. You need code that works that you
can actively improve on. And that's
often more important than simply writing
it. And when you're testing, the problem
is often that if you run the code, you
don't exactly see what happened when it
ran. And it doesn't matter how smart the
model is if it has to guess what
happened. It's missing crucial context.
And that's why today I want to show you
a tool that gives you that missing
context. And that's Jam, the sponsor of
today's video. So here's how Jam works.
If you're in the process of testing a
new feature and something doesn't go as
expected, instead of having to do the
classic AI debugging thing where you
take screenshots, copy console output,
or sometimes you're even trying to
reproduce the buck yourself, instead of
all that, you can simply use JAM's
instant replay. And then here's what
happens. This is really interesting. Jam
takes the last few seconds of what
happened on your screen, and it fills
out the entire ticket for you, including
technical details and a step-by-step
reproduction and even a suggested fix.
It also automatically adds all network
requests and console outputs. All the
things that you would usually be
manually pulling together to give the AI
model a chance to debug efficiently. And
it packages all that in one sharable
link. They even packaged all of this in
an MCP so you can easily call this from
within cursor or clot code, giving all
these apps the ability to essentially
look at everything that matters from the
screen recording to the logs and really
understand what went wrong to give the
AI model a chance to fix it. Need that
context anywhere else? one with one
click you can get it to Jira Linear
Asana notion or GitHub you name it.
Honestly I can't stress how much time
this actually saves even if you're not
doing this work yourself if you're
working with developer rather than just
saying hey I tried the form and it
doesn't work and then them following up
with multiple questions it's so much
easier if somebody's testing the app to
actually have this at your disposal so
you can hand it off to a developer or
hand it off to an AI to really paint the
full picture. I've been sitting here and
copying console logs and taking
screenshots since forever now and this
is just a better way to do it. And
recently I worked with a developer and
we went through this entire process many
times and it was such a tedious process.
As I learned about Jam I was genuinely
upset that I didn't have it for that
project. So if you're a developer
project manager or QA save time and
headaches in your next development
project, go check out JAM today. You can
get started on a free plan by clicking
the link at the top of this video's
description. Thanks again to JAM for
sponsoring this video. And now on to the
next piece of Aan news that you can use.
Okay, so this one as a passionate video
creator is incredible. This is something
that back in the day when I was manually
editing videos. If you're not familiar,
in my early 20s, I started out by doing
cold outreach to various nightclubs in
the city that I lived in, Vienna. And
then from around 21 to 23, I was
creating two free event videos a week.
Then I moved to corporate events,
weddings, course production, and so on.
But really, music was an essential part
all along the way. And the only way to
get music for my videos back then was
licensing it from various sites. And now
you might know that with AI you can
generate it. But also there's all these
new tools like this one that we're
seeing now. And to be clear, this is not
a first. But this 11 Labs music model
has been just so good that I can't wait
to try this out. It's a videoto music
tool and it does exactly that. And we're
going to try it now. We're going to
upload a video and see what kind of
music it generates for it. So I just
have some random AI videos laying around
here. Let's see what it does with them.
This is one smooth animation that I kind
of like. Going to upload this. And
without even logging in, this should
give us a song for it.
[Music]
Oo. Yeah, that is so fitting. I wasn't
even sure what I would put there myself,
but this type of tool, it makes me want
to create unique videos again. Okay,
let's try one more. There's this little
video of, I don't know, animated me
waving. Let's see what it does here. I
suppose this vibe should be more of a
elevator music or or something friendly.
Yeah, exactly right. Like a corporate
jingle.
Okay, I have one more clip right here.
Want to see what it does? I mean, it's
the pulp fiction scene.
That is so fitting. It kind of nailed
all three of those. So, you can try that
without even logging in. That's kind of
nice. And relating to that story, I'm
just going to quickly point out that
they also made their 11 music product
available for the API now. Wasn't the
case last week. And they dropped a bunch
of guides in their documentation. So, if
you wonder how to prompt it, how to
really get the most out of this tool,
well, they shared various best practices
here in their documentation. All right,
let's move on. Google made a bunch of
announcements. None of that is really
available yet, but there's one thing in
particular that I really wanted to
highlight in this video. They're
announced their Pixel 10 with a bunch of
AI features and an AI focused chip. It's
basically a AI focused phone. And they
also had some Google Home announcements.
But there was one thing in here that I
just really wanted you to see so you can
prepare for this future where you can do
phone calls and it live translates into
any language. I mean this phone is going
to be coming as soon as October. And to
do low latency live translation, you
just need a lot of computing power on
the device. And apparently the new chip
makes this possible. And you can
translate between all of these languages
right here. This one in particular I
just can't wait to try as soon as that's
available. I could use that in Portugal
dealing with the super slow bureaucracy
where I don't even understand it. many
times. Okay, next up we got to talk
about a trend that I absolutely love and
that's the unification of standards
across the entire generative AI space.
In this case, I'm talking about this
agents.m MD format which is looking to
be the universal format for all agent
context files. And I think this Twitter
post perfectly outlines the utility of
this idea. Shatien, the creator of the
popular front-end library, shares that
this is what agentic projects commonly
look like. You have a bunch of different
rules. You have instructions, you have a
clot.md if you're working with clot
code. And this new agent.mnd format is
looking to solve that. And the open dev
account even acknowledged this week. And
that's basically the story. It's just
looking to unify all of these context
documents that agents use to maintain
their memory and give you more
consistent results across time. There
are essential part of the context that
these agents work with. And I hope to
see this adopted by all the coding
platforms because then it's going to
make a lot of stuff interoperable. And
now with this file tool, you could
easily transfer the different tools and
context that you have in certain apps
and pick the work up with a different
tool, which is just not the case right
now. There's quite a bit of lock in as
every system functions a bit
differently. And I just love this idea
of a future where everything is
interoperable, open, and the power lays
in the user's hand. And this is a step
in that direction. And that's why I
really wanted to cover this. And now on
to this week's quick hits. There's a few
stories that I thought were worth your
attention. And the first one is chatb
typos. Matt Wolf was tweeting about
this. This was a hot topic in our
community this week and multiple members
conferred that they have this same issue
of chat chip making typos, something
we've never seen before. What this
really means is that they're tinkering
with the model as it is live. They're
not saying what they're changing, but
they're switching it up just like they
have since the release of GPT5. But this
is a really weird one because we've
never seen chat make typos before. I
mean, what kind of training data are
they giving it that typos are in there?
If I think about that, that's got to be
conversational data. you know, like
chats or Discord server rooms. You're
not going to get typos in books or video
transcripts or even blog posts. Hm. Not
sure what to really make of that, but
just wanted to tell you about it.
Another story that I always love is
these gaming benchmarks for LLMs. And
there's been a change. GPT5 is the new
king because it actually managed to
finish Pokémon Red. Okay, so for some
fun facts around this, the entire
162hour run cost about $3,500
in API credits. So, we did some research
and we couldn't find exact times on this
exact benchmark to compare to GPT5. But
I remember that the Gemini model got a
comparable results to 03. And there is
this graph that compares it to the 03
performance. As you can see, it took
17,000 steps for 03 to complete this
whereas GP5 did it in 6,000. Just
another way to look at AI progress and
how quickly things are coming along. And
then also I thought it's super
interesting that OpenAI launched this
initiative to launch chat GPT in India.
They have a brand new subscription tier
that costs $4 for 10 times higher
message limits than the free version. I
want to see the entire world benefit
from this technology and these use
cases. And I can tell you already from
my YouTube analytics, I've seen that
India is the country that is consuming
English AI content the most outside of
the Western world. Sure, there's a lot
of people who speak English, but also I
think there's a tech literacy and a
curiosity. And I hope that the big
companies keep serving up plans like
this to create more opportunity,
especially in the software space. And
that right there is pretty much
everything we have for this week. It was
a bit of a shorter one, but hey, it's
summer. This is how I expected things to
go. But then we got the week in early
August where everything dropped at the
same time. At this point, I want to
share one thing about the channel, and
that is that we're refocusing on new
YouTube content. We have several very
interesting and higher production value
videos in production right now. And I
can't wait to share some highv value
tutorials and super long- form content
that teaches at a level of depth that we
haven't covered before on this channel.
So, keep your eyes peeled for that. And
other than that, we'll keep doing this
show every Friday. My name is Igor and I
hope you have a wonderful